Four of that spot. Yeah. Not what I expected to hear on Friday. First and foremost, regardless of the races, the playoffs, the waivers, our our real wishes when Chase gets back
and be back at 09:00.
>> But I've been in a situation like this where your driver was injured or sick and it's
hard on everybody's hard on
behind the wheel of a race car, why wouldn't he afford the opportunity to go out and then snowboard something that can be dangerous? What is the reaction from the driver when you hear a question like that? Yeah. I mean, I'm gonna you you never want something that needs to happen, you know? But at the end of the day,
>> and it can be dangerous at times as well. So I feel like it's very important to disconnect from racing a little bit. And every single driver has different COVID, different distraction, different kind of training.
>> I mean, it's very We try to be as safe as possible, but there is always a limit at risk without the partner. The next step will be the ruling on the medical waiver there. Yeah, if I talk to Max Carr about that this weekend, they said, yeah, we have received the request from Hendrick Motorsports. They go back. They evaluate all the information. I can't imagine that they will not give it to him. I think back to 2015,
Kyle Busch injured in the Xfinity series race at Daytona in February. Yes, he came back to the all star race but he officially didn't come back to race number 12 at Charlotte Motor Speedway.
One race number 16
but remember, back then, you had to get to the top 30 in points That is going away. Chase out against the waiver. He comes back and wins in the regular season. He should be in the playoffs. Most importantly, we want Chase to be unwell. Get healthy. We hope to see you back in the track soon. So Josh Barry gets the opportunity where we chase not driving to drive that night car on Sunday afternoon. This is a very difficult circumstance for a driver that's going for the Xfinity championship. Yes, same situation as a nine team. He gets on an airplane and fly Las Vegas. He's thinking, oh, I'm doing driving Xfinity series rakes on Saturday. He and my family's gotta go back home And think about it. You're stepping in the most popular drivers number nine car. You only have two cup starts. You have never
raced the next gen car. Unfortunately, this was in the race right here. Gets in a turn to what we saw Kyle Busch do it twice. But when I think about a twenty ninth place finish, I go, whoop, that's the other teams ran one, two, three. But again, this situation right here in a race that only had four cautions and in a race that 35 of the drivers of the 36 that started were still out there, he did exactly what he needed to do, run as many laps as possible and be there again. You know, the cup series is very difficult. Competition is very difficult. Even when you prepare yourself, even when you do simulator, even when you watch film and you watch so
We got the coverage for the box 03:00 Eastern side. We look forward to what is kind of our first short track race of the year. Even though the officially needs a file, it's not a short track with that. I am called to order the Andover
>> Inland,
Wetlands,
and Water Courses Commission.
I see on the call
Commissioners Larson, Nashke, Monroe, and Fife. Of course, I'm here too, so we got a full board,
alternate Smith not
present.
Are there any
suggested changes
or additions
to the agenda?
>> I would like to add a brief discussion of the work
taking place
at 409
Lake Road.
That's Lot 22.
>> Okay, should we add that to the you want to add that to the agent report? We can, yep.
Okay, so we got a motion like a second.
I'll second that Commissioner Monroe seconds to add that item to the agenda that will be then.
We'll call it 8B.
Just to make sure that it's duly noted.
Anything else?
Okay, and moving on, we have approval of the
regular meeting minutes
from our previous meeting Monday, February 6.
And
again, those were distributed,
should be in hand.
I'll give you a second to run through them again and ask if there are any
additions or corrections
to the
minutes
as
posted.
Okay,
anybody have anything?
I've got a couple of items I noted when I was reviewing them earlier.
First of all, in
item
one. What
was that a little static?
Okay,
there was a.
Okay.
It was once again a public meeting, not a hearing in the call to order.
Okay,
in
the roll call, seating of alternates,
Ed Smith is
an alternate,
not a regular member.
Okay, in Item nine,
which was the other business,
commission vacancies,
there's a sentence that says George Eliot motioned to move Duncan Fife
as a regular member of the IWCC,
sorry, WWC.
Two things there. First of all, it was a motion to appoint
and the spelling of Fife
should be with a Y rather than an I.
Then with an I, would be fifa as in fifa drum corps.
Okay,
let's see now, is there anything else? Oh, and finally, in the footnote,
the motions are not officially approved by the IWWC.
I think you're mixing your commissions there, Carol. We have
our own authority over our minutes, and we do not rely on our companion agency.
Okay? Okay, noted. Thank you. Okay, that's all I had.
So, if there are no other
revisions,
corrections, I would ask for a motion to approve those minutes.
>> I'll make a motion to approve the minutes as amended.
Okay, and a second.
I'll second them. Okay,
>> got that.
And
I'll take a quick roll call. Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Mr. Mashke?
>> Commissioner Monroe?
Aye.
Commissioner Fife?
And I also vote aye, so the motion carries,
five-zero-zero.
And moving on.
Okay, there's oh, I see a member of the public, so I will ask for public comment if there's anything on our agenda.
>> And excuse me, George, may I have Hank's
last name?
>> Who?
Hank? Hank, that's Hank Gruner, G R U N E R,
who is with the with the Conservation
Commission.
Thank you.
>> Okay,
so no public comment. The next item is old business,
the permit application,
IWWC
20 three-one,
given to us previously
by Jay Tuttle, the town of Andover Public Works Director,
and the permit,
general nature of which is to cover routine activities
associated
with right of way drainages.
We had an extensive discussion of this, of course, at the last meeting.
However, some revisions
from the original application
project description
were advanced as a result of discussions
at the meeting and then subsequently between
Agent Wagner and Mr. Tuttle.
So, with that background, I'll ask, since I see that Agent Wagner is on the call and not Mr. Tuttle, if Agent Wagner would
direct
us to
the important changes
that were made in the application documentation.
>> Alright. Can you hear me alright?
Yep. I had to switch to my phone for some reason. I wasn't getting any audio on my computer,
so
Yeah.
>> Yeah. We
work with Jay to
kinda
make it more a little bit more detailed, limit
the the scope of the work, kinda in accordance with
commissioner Larson's comments.
So the big changes were the
last two bullet points on the,
project description,
which were, they said, repair
or replacement of defective
drainage structures and or systems to include catch basins, culverts,
and or wing wall, the inlets or outlet, and any drainage pipes in the same location.
And we
deleted
the drainage structures in our system,
culverts,
any drainage pipes in the same location, and then we added another bullet point under that that said
replacement of culverts or drainage pipes 24 inches or less in diameter that do not contain a watercourse as defined in section 2.36
of Andover's in the wetland regulation.
Let's see what else do we do.
I think the other changes in the last paragraph,
we added the
an individual wetlands permit application will be filed for any public works department projects that do not fall under the scope of this general permit, such as new projects,
replacement of culverts containing watercourses or culverts greater than 24 inches in diameter,
or projects that require significant redesign of existing structures or alterations of drainage flow.
So those are the changes in wording.
Okay.
Any questions or comments from any commissioners here?
>> I guess I still got a little bit of a concern on the,
it's the
new fifth bullet down
where we're
talking about repair or replacement of defective catch basins, I got that,
for end
or wing walls at inlets and outlets.
In my concern
there is,
you know, I think the wing wall
could be a pretty extensive
project
in close proximity
to wetlands.
At least the one that I have in mind is the
wing wall
where Basola Road comes into Lake Road and it's crumbling away,
that's
a significant project with a huge culvert. I was thinking maybe the wing wall on a 24
inches pipe or less, but
you know a project of that magnitude I would think would still warrant
you know bringing an application
to the commission.
>> Wouldn't that be covered by the
size of the culvert
and the fact that it carries a water course in this situation?
You
know, of those being
circumstances
that would require
a specific
application.
>> I don't know that the culvert needs to be repaired.
I think it's just the wing wall that's crumbling and falling apart out there. And that's why when we broke that out,
I
got concerned on that.
I don't know if work needs to be done on the culvert itself or whatever.
All I know is if we were to go out and
and do whatever to that wing wall, think that that warrants
a
permit
regardless
of
whether we're going to work on the culvert or the drainage pipe.
>> Yeah, I think I take your point.
Do you have a suggestion for modifying the language?
This is in the nature and purpose of project document,
right? The one that's
titled IWWC
twenty three-one
General Permit and over DPW
project description?
>> Yep, I think the same words.
Right. The same words are in the
the permit itself
too.
On page two of the permit they've got the
same six bullets that are here under this nature project.
>> Okay, well, the salient language would be in
the actual permit.
So again, you a
for how we could
modify that language.
>> Well, I think my
recommendation would be to just eliminate the words or indoor wing walls at inlets or outlets.
That still allows,
you know, to repair or replacement of defective catch basins
without
anything here, which is, you know, what I thought was a reasonable approach. You know, I don't think we've
I don't think we've overtaxed
the public works department by, you know, having them come to the commission
too often.
>> It's true. There haven't been that many applications
before the Commission in the past few years,
and there were probably none at all before that,
given the way things used to work.
So
yeah, if you feel that it would be not
too restrictive,
I don't know where or what,
how much, wind wall or how much end wall
repair would certainly, if they're gonna go after culvert
in less than 24 inches, they're almost invariably going to be
dealing
with
some
ancillary
structure, right?
And I think that
we have to give them some reasonable leeway
to
get the kind of work done.
If you're talking about catch basins and so forth, you know, other
essentially masonry
type structures, whether they're
stacked stone or concrete,
know, it's hard to see where they could
well,
you know, would
those occur
only
in larger
projects?
>> I mean, are we trying to do it with the regular maintenance
portion of it? So, that doesn't sound like that's a regular maintenance.
>> Well,
that's exactly
the question I'm asking. I don't know if it's
if some of the kinds of, you know, if activities involving
headwalls and windwalls would be
part of their routine maintenance,
you know, going into a drainage system and
trying to correct problem with flow or deterioration
of the structure
with age and salt and all of those things.
Agent Wagner, do you have, any sense of
work that there might be a cutoff?
Again, I don't want to just completely exclude things
that we don't need to exclude.
>> Yeah. I was trying to think of,
if we could
reword it to, you know, replacement of culverts or drainage pipes
24 inches or less. If you could add the
associated
catch basins
or and their wing walls because, you know, if you if you could limit it to or you could just leave that out. I mean,
not sure
if those small drainage pipes have wing walls. I'm just trying to think of an example of one that I've seen. Yeah. I I don't know the engineers. Those are probably the the larger culverts anyway, which wouldn't fall under this, the ones that had water forces in them. And
>> again, the purpose of having a two or three year review thing is if we find out
that we
miss the boat somewhere on this thing and
there are a bunch of wing walls on the smaller pipes,
know, we can fix it.
The only example that I'm aware of is the one at Mazola Road and it's a huge wing wall.
Right, right.
>> Yeah. I mean, if you could if you wanted to strike that out and then see how it went, I mean, I'm sure
you probably could or, know,
because, I mean, the replacement of culverts or drainage pipes is 24 inches. The last step bottom statement would probably cover the stuff that's associated with those things, and then, you know, then there wouldn't be any confusion, I guess. That was my thinking.
Yeah.
So you could and then the the bullet above that could just say repair of or replacement of defective catch basin, and then that would be it.
Would that make sense?
I would agree with that. Okay.
>> Okay, I think in order to get our ducks in a row here,
we should have
a motion on the floor to
approve
the permit application,
because then the
modifications
that we're making
can be entered as amendments
to the motion, okay?
>> The only question I had was there
was some talk on the last meeting about the length of time,
you know, two to three years versus the five years, and it looks like it's written for five. We'll address that in just a moment, Janet. Okay. That's
>> definitely going to come up. First,
I'd like to have a motion
to approve the application because then we can proceed
to amend the application
and have it on the record as a formal process.
>> I will make a motion to approve the application for permit
IWWC
20.
>> Okay.
Okay. I got a second on that.
I'll second it. Okay. So, I moved and seconded.
Now, can, again,
as a as a motion,
Commissioner Larsen, if you would
again move to amend
the
permit
and application
to
delete
references
to end or wing walls.
>> I would like to make a motion to amend the
application
under the typical maintenance activities
that would be covered under this permit
on the
fifth bullet down to remove the words or end or wing walls at inlets
or
outlets.
>> And
that will also apply to the,
well,
we've got the document,
that's a general permit
and over DPW
permit draft, and the revision that we're looking at is
from
March I'm sorry, February 9.
So we're looking to, again, eliminate the language from that as well, right?
Yes.
>> Okay.
So we got the motion to amend.
Any other
and a motion seconded. Do we have any
discussion
on that point? I mean, we've already talked about it, so if there's any further discussion.
Okay, if not, I'll call for a vote on the amendment. Commissioner Larson.
>> Well, did you want to address
any of the other any One other items or just amendment at a time. Okay. Okay.
>> That way we can really keep a clear record of of where we're going. Okay. I got you.
So,
Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Matsky?
Commissioner Munro?
Aye.
Commissioner Fipes?
>> And I also vote vying. So,
motion to amend carries 500.
Moving on,
there were other things to consider. One that Commissioner Manski just brought up, the duration
of the permit that is currently blank,
so we have to fill in the blank,
and I would like that in the form of well, we can have some discussion first, but we'll need a motion
to set the duration
of the
permit
to add
to the record.
I think there was general consensus at the last meeting that five years might be a bit much.
I'll throw out a number that I think would be reasonable, and that would be three.
>> I'll make a motion to amend
the permit to be valid for three years.
>> Okay,
got that.
And could I have a second?
I'll second it. Okay, so I'm moving to second. I think it's a reasonable length of time because, you know, again, as we pointed out, we haven't had a lot of applications from
the
Department of Public Works for these kinds of activities. So, I think, you know, we have to have a long enough
period of time
to see how it plays out.
And again, as Commissioner Larson pointed out, we may find that there are routine activities
that we have excluded
from the permits,
or there may be activities
that
are
perhaps a little more than we had anticipated.
So, we have motion second for
three years. Any other comments?
So, again, I'll take a roll
call on that. Commissioner Larson?
Aye. Commissioner Mashke?
Aye. Commissioner Monroe?
Aye. And Commissioner Fife?
And I also vote aye, so the motion carries 500.
So, the permit duration will be three
years.
Now,
do we have any further discussion,
suggestions for amendments,
or
alterations on the
main motion, which is to approve the permit.
I have one other
comment. Go ahead.
>> And that we
have attached to the permit
the
standard
conditions of approval.
And
Correct.
>> I
know some of those conditions,
I'm not sure
if they'd approve, if they'd be valid or not. Maybe it's not the biggest deal in the world.
But when I looked at item six,
this approval is for the activity within the regulated areas surrounding a wetland or watercourse is indicated on the following map.
Yeah. Don't need revision.
And I felt
that
if we could comply with all the rest of them, I don't know that we could comply with that one.
>> Not since it's a permit for any area of drainage in town, so it would have to be the map of the town
and its wetlands
and drainage systems, which we don't have.
>> So So to make it technically correct, I would recommend that we eliminate
standard condition number six.
Okay,
then the formal motion.
>> I'll make a motion that we eliminate standard
condition number six
from permit IWWC
23Dash01.
>> Okay.
And a second?
I'll second. Okay. So we got a motion and a second to, eliminate that particular
item six on our standard conditions.
Any
discussion?
Seeing none, ask for the vote. Doctor. Larson?
Aye. Mr. Mashke?
Aye.
Mr. Monroe?
Aye. Thank you, Mr. Five.
I also vote aye, so the motion carries
five zero zero.
I did have one
questioncomment
in thelet's
see, I've got to find that on there.
Sorry.
>> Okay,
the
permit
and thewell, at least theyeah,
the project description portion talks about
brush removal in swales, ditches, and water courses in and around drainage culverts where normal flow has been obstructed by overgrown vegetation.
My comment there would be, do we want to set any limit
on the distance
from the drainage feature?
SayI
am thinking back, for example, on the
Shawty Mill Road where
they obviously had to go off road
to clear
drainage swales
that were feeding into a culvert system.
And
you know, there are, of course,
are bounds to how far they can go
within the right of way
per se.
And Mr. Tuttle described
consulting
with landowners,
know, abutting landowners
and securing
consent
if he felt he needed to go further
than the right of way
to get the work done.
Again, I'm just throwing this out. I don't have any particular
thoughts about how far or what
boundaries might be
appropriate if they're
in fact needed at all. So,
just,
you know, again asking for comment there, does that seem like a reasonable
restriction to place on the
road cruise activities?
>> Well, I I had read that, you know, thinking
that
if the removing
brush
from where normal flow has been obstructed,
it can't be very far from where the normal flow goes. We're not talking about
in a flood situation or something.
I
thought Jay was just talking about,
you know, removing it
from where it accumulates
in
these,
you know, water flow paths.
So I was okay with that
the way it was written.
>> Okay.
I'm, as I said, you're tossing it out as an idea. Other comments on that?
No. I haven't made a motion so that we don't really have to act on that comment.
If there are any other comments.
>> I have one
here, Elliot. I would think that, like, say if there was a tree down,
like, you know, even if it's a 100 yards away, if it's there's a tree down right in the middle of your culvert that's feeding your
your drainage system, you would think that you just wanna get it out of there as fast as you can.
That's what I would is that what you're asking? Those kind of things like a tree down? Again,
>> if they're it's
hard to see how again,
you're you're right. A tree fall,
then it falls
in the drainage swale
or
in theI'm
thinking more of if it came into a water course
that fed
you know, coming down
to
a drainage feature. Again, thinking about the Shawty Mill Road project, there was a definite water. It was a seasonal water course
that
required some work, and that's how we came to note it.
But again, accumulation of brush, tree fall, anything like that, yeah, in the immediate vicinity
of the
drainage feature, yeah, that makes sense.
But if
it's a water course
specifically,
I wonder if we want to have a little
restriction
on that.
Again, whether it's a seasonal water course or a continuous water course. Yeah, if brush
fall on
the culvert crossing on, say, Stout Brook RoadI
mean, Stout Brook Creek at Townsend,
something like that, we would expect
the
road crew to be able to clear that. But if it's, you know, 100 feet upstream,
yeah, it's going to alter the watercourse flow, but
do we want them
just charging off into the brush to do that?
I guess this is one of those things where maybe we should just let it play out
and
see if,
you know,
three years' time will be soon enough to decide
if any adjustments are needed. Right. Okay.
Other than that, I don't have any other comments. Does anyone else can,
sort of last call,
comments,
suggested revisions,
and so forth.
So, we can return to a vote on the main motion to approve the permit
with the modifications
in the timeline specified.
Commissioner Larson?
>> Are you looking for a vote or a motion? A vote.
Vote.
Aye.
Okay. Commissioner Mashke?
Commissioner Monroe?
Aye.
>> And Commissioner Fife?
I also vote aye, so the motion carries five-zero-zero,
and the permit will be issued.
Commissioner or
Agent Wagner, I expect he'll be in touch with
Mr. Tuttle
and work out the, you know, point out the details
and of course be in contact with him
as
time progresses,
and work under this general permit
actually gets undertaken.
Okay, moving on. We don't have any new business, so no new applications
to consider.
And now for
agenda item eight, the agent report,
including the
additional
comments requested by Commissioner Larson. So, Adrian Wagner?
>> I
didn't hear the, first part when my audio wasn't working, but I'm assuming commissioner Larson wanted to hear about,
409 Lake Road.
Is that correct? Yes.
Okay.
I'll do that. I have that at the end.
See, I I've been trying to get in touch with
the owner of Scott's Tree Farm about cleaning up that
tree debris in the pond.
I've
sent I got some notes here.
Let's see. I visited, talked to him. I think I updated you guys about that. That was back in October. In January, I mailed him a letter.
Didn't hear back.
In February, I called him. I didn't hear anything.
So towards the end of the month, I found
another email address and emailed him. Finally got a response from him saying that he's well, his employees are laid off in the winter
and that he would work on the cleanup when he got back for the season.
So
once he got some employees back, which I think
at this point, because we're getting into springtime,
it would probably be best to do it in
July or August, which is what I told him.
So, yeah, I've been basically documenting
everything.
I've got photos.
So,
you know, my
thought is to
push in the summer. And, if nothing happens, then I got everything kind of set up for, you know, taking more action
on that. Just try and get some some of it cleaned up.
And then,
so I got another one,
Route 6, Connecticut Meditation Center. We're driving by and seeing the
big statue and an enclosure that was built there. It's within
a 100 feet of a brook. So I sent them an email that they needed to apply for an
aid and approved
permit
for work in Upland Review area.
They responded
quickly
saying that they were gonna work on an application to get it into me.
I don't have it yet. That was last week.
I got a pending permit application for ground mounted solar panels in the Upland Review area at 187
Lake Road.
Still waiting for a bunch of information on that. The guy is, the homeowner's working on it himself. He is in Florida. He's kinda not in a big rush,
so he hasn't
you know, I'll post that on the website once I get everything in. He he filled it out on a perm, but it had hardly any information. So
we're working on that, getting a more complete application.
I got another one last week that's probably coming in. That's, 115 Lakeside Drive as a wall repair in the Upland Review area.
It's, I think it's about 60 feet from the lake.
So,
they got a plan in there. They're working on getting their permit link application in. I'll get that up on the website once I get everything for that.
And then
409 Lake Road,
they started clearing
that lot on Friday.
It made quite a mess.
Commissioner Larson's emailed me about it, and,
public works act also
asked me,
if I knew about it. So I went and checked that this afternoon, took a few pictures.
Yeah. They went in and they kind of sticking
to the
limits of clearing
as far as going across the wetland, but they don't have a
tracking pad. They don't have any erosion control in yet.
So I called the builder.
He wanted me to give him till the end of the week to get it taken care of.
So
thought I'd just see what see what happens, see if we can clean it up. He said he got a had to get the log out of the way so he could put the tracking pad in and then start working on getting the silt fence and getting the wetlands crossing built.
It's kind of a flat area, so I don't know if the erosion risk is is super high right now, but it is it is quite a mess if you drive by it.
And that's
that's what I got for the report. So any questions on that?
>> Well,
were were you informed, Joe, that two days
prior to the start of the work is our permit required?
>> Yeah. I saw that. That's
they didn't no. They didn't inform me. They were I mean, they he was in here doing the building permit, so I kinda knew it was gonna start soon, but I didn't get a call anyway.
So, yeah, there was Yeah.
A few few things in the order of the permit and then the conditions that we added that haven't really been followed so far.
So that's kinda what I what I let him know when I called him today.
>> Because I know when we approved this,
you know, and we were talking about
starting to work
during the dry summer months.
Now I couldn't find,
know, I guess maybe that's bad on us that we didn't
specify anything in the restrictions. I can't find where he violated anything there. I don't think that made it into the approval because I remember he added all those conditions onto the plan. I don't remember seeing that. Yeah. And but we certainly we talked about it and the expectation was that it would be done. Now I know when I went by Friday, they had a big wood chipper, you know, and it was stuck in the mud there. They couldn't get it out.
>> They picked a terrible time to start. I think. Yep.
>> And so
I
went back and looked at what the permit did say,
I would have thought that if they'd come and had a discussion with you two days before they started,
we could have alleviated
a lot of that stuff. And I don't know if it's a good story that they can't get the tracking pad in there now.
I think they can. They got the logs off to the side. Certainly,
you know, they're getting all the heavy equipment,
you know, through there into the back and
that's
what I was expecting to be, you know, put down first is that, I know, you know,
we don't want to fill the wetland with
riprap
but
we we don't want all the mud going out onto the road and get washed away and all that kind of stuff so I was kind of expecting
that to be step two. Step one is they talk to you. Step two, they put in the tracking pad
and not make the big mess that they did there.
>> Yeah. And that's
a know Jay drove. I think he drove by there today and
Jim House, he was gonna give him a call to to try and push him on the tracking pad.
At
least get that in
to protect the road and stuff. That's I mean, it's not really a wetlands issue protecting the road, but still it's part of the plan. And Yep.
Trying to chew it in order is is kind of important. It kind of gives you
an idea of how things are going to go, you know. And remember
>> when we approved that permit,
you know, that ridiculous Larson fella made a big point about the fact that we make these plans and then the people who execute them
never even look at them. They just go out and do whatever it is they think they want to do.
And everybody said, nope, that's not going to happen here.
And
it seems to me that that's exactly what happened here. Yeah, it's it's frustrating.
>> We don't have any much mechanism
to
enforce those provisions, like especially the notification
provisions.
It's
all well that
Agent Wagner has a general sense that they're going be starting,
but that's not the same as being notified we're going to be starting in a couple of days. Well, that gives Joe the opportunity to ask some questions.
>> Like he can go take a look at it and see, oh, where's the tracking pad?
>> Yeah,
out there, walk the site. Yeah,
those kind of things are
helpful to do, make sure everybody's on the same page.
>> Okay, nope, I just,
as you know, I walk by there just about every day and
said nope, that wasn't what I had in mind when we approved the permit.
>> Yeah, I was kind of
pushing him to get it done. I mean, I I wanna I don't wanna it it annoys me too because he put a lot of time and effort into this stuff, and then people just do whatever they want. So if nothing's
done at the end of the week,
I don't know. I might have to take more action. And
>> it often
falls short of what you would want to consider an enforcement action.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. We could. I mean, in the future, there's there's
I mean, we could do some kind of bond with those type of things.
You know? You can't do that with this permit, but maybe that's something to consider in the future
if you had to take a little cash deposit from them to, you know, hold on to it to make sure everything, all the conditions are followed,
maybe something to consider future project.
It might help their memory of
attention.
Good point. Absolutely, there should be some recourse.
>> Okay. That's all that's all I wanted to you know, I just
wanted to make sure that we all had
similar expectations
of
that we ought to follow
guidance that we work hard to come up with.
>> Point well taken.
Any other comments on the agent report?
I hadn't realized that Connecticut Meditation
Center was in Andover,
and we certainly wouldn't want that guilt Buddha
to be left uncovered.
I hope that they do get their permit taken care of.
So,
let's see now.
Next, other business,
really just some announcements. Remember, commission vacancy is a perennial.
We finally have five commissioners.
We still need alternate,
especially since,
well,
Ed Smith has been listed as an alternate more or less pro form a since he was willing to attend meetings if we couldn't get a quorum otherwise,
but
he hasn't attended
otherwise.
And I think that we could stand to have
an alternate who actually attended
meetings.
That's the point of being an alternate.
And
also, oh, along those same lines,
I
will probably not continue on the
commission
at the end of my current term,
and you may have noticed that the
the Ender website
lists commission vacancies
now as
or commission terms as expiring
in November
2023,
contrary
to my expectation based on the charter,
which says that our terms run from 07/01/2021,
to 06/30/2023,
whereupon, of course, we may be reappointed.
Now, I understand that for elected commissions,
such as planning and zoning,
the
new election cycle, having
municipal elections in November
rather than May.
That
would require a reset for the terms
for elected commissions,
but we are an appointed commission,
so I'm not sure how that's all going to play out. I
inquired.
Carol Lee is out of the office, and so I'm going to check back
in a week or so and see if I can find out more about that.
But as I say, as far as I'm concerned right now, the charter,
rules
and our bylaws,
are geared toward an appointment from
July 1 through June 30.
So,
it remains to be seen whether your terms will continue
through November.
I trust that everyone has been informed of the need for
training,
mandated training
on sexual harassment.
It was circulated
widely,
and I hope everybody will comply.
I
sat through the state of Connecticut
CHRO
training.
I found a pro tip here. If you haven't done the training yet, You can read faster than they can talk, so if you turn YouTube sound off and turn the
playback
speed to 2x,
you can, zip through
in half the time.
>> That violates the rule, George. It has to take at least two hours.
>> They
said a two hour training session,
right?
And, you know, if you look at the timelines
on those videos, it is two hours.
Well,
yeah, there
are advantages to Zoom training as opposed to having to sit in the room, you know?
Okay, that's all on that. Again, as you see, I'll
continue
to
make inquiries about the
terms of office and whether or not you can expect to
be
re enlisted
in July
or November.
Any other general
items
for the Commission?
Okay, seeing none,
our next regular meeting will be on Monday, April 3, same time, same
place virtually.
And with that, I can ask for a motion to adjourn.
I'll make a motion to adjourn.
Second.
>> And I will second it. Okay, that's a nondebatable motion.
So,
signify by saying aye.
Motion is unanimous,
and we can now stand adjourned.
I thank you all for participating.
I'm glad this was a nice short meeting, and
hopefully, though, the Commission will have some work to do in subsequent months, maybe when construction activities start picking up.
So, I will
look forward to seeing you in April,
and until then, keep well.
>> You too, everyone. Bye, everybody. Have a good night. Bye all.